# JOHN COLELLA

**4** 631 838 8222

₱ Brooklyn, NY

in

www.linkedin.com/in/johnmcolella

• https://github.com/jmcolella

## **SUMMARY**

I am a web developer skilled in building apps using Rails, React, Redux JavaScript and HTML/CSS. I have a passion for design and love working the full stack to create meaningful projects. With experience working in fastpaced environments, I'm a team player who can work efficiently with others to meet hard deadlines. I have excellent communication and organizational skills along with analytical experience that has proven effective in collaborative environments.

# **SKILLS**

#### LANGUAGES

JavaScript (ES5/ES6)

Ruby

\_

HTML5

CSS3

SQL

## FRAMEWORKS/TOOLS

React

Redux

Webpack

Rails

Bootstrap

Jekyll

Sinatra

# **PLATFORMS**

Google Maps API

Yelp API

Twitter API

#### **DATABASES**

PostgresSQL

SQLite

ActiveRecord

## **TESTING**

**RSpec** 

Jasmine

Capybara

#### **METHODOLOGIES**

Object Oriented Design
Test Driven Development

# **EMPLOYMENT**

Front End Developer

SICORE TECH

Farmingdale, NY Aug 2016 to Current

- · Oversee the design and build process of a browser-based user interface for an embedded securities software.
- Utilize the React framework to organize and construct the interface along with necessary node modules.
- · Assist embedded systems engineer with building a custom HTTP server in C.
- Implement JavaScript websockets and write C code to handle communication with the server.

#### **SUITS AND SANDALS**

Brooklyn, NY Oct 2016 to Nov 2016

Freelance Front End Developer

- Take lead on updating portions of Shopify e-commerce website for BlueButterflyGF
- Incorporate mockups from design lead to develop new custom templates for collections and products
- · Update Shopify backend with new products and collections to best reflect client's store front needs
- Refactor custom JavaScript from previous developer to fit new user interface for selecting protein meal options

#### KATTEN MUCHIN ROSENMAN LLP

New York, NY Jun 2013 to Mar 2016

· Partner with leadership and associates to secure loans for multi-million dollar real estate investments.

- Manage the organization and transferral of legal documents between attorneys and clients.
- · Liaise with internal and external parties to ensure post-closing procedures and deadlines were secured.
- Analyze legal documentation to facilitate drafting new documents for future projects.
- Oversee the integration and training of new paralegal hires into the firm.

TRIBECA FILM

New York, NY Jan 2015 to Aug 2015

Acquisitions/Marketing Intern

- Generate performance reports for video-on-demand data to understand national market for Tribeca Film titles.
- Compile master revenue report of external independent titles for leadership to determine market size for competitor's titles.
- Analyze marketing practices of major video-on-demand vendors to best strategize promotion of Tribeca titles with these vendors.
- Take lead on portions of marketing outreach by analyzing social media statistics to determine best business partners for particular Tribeca titles.

## **MAGNOLIA PICTURES**

New York, NY Jan 2013 to May 2013

Marketing/Publicity Intern

- · Serve as first point-of-contact and main liaison for guests via e-mail, phone and at the Magnolia office front desk.
- Compile press information regarding Magnolia releases for marketing to track performance of Magnolia titles.
- Research business contacts for targeted Magnolia releases and update database with information for future use.
- Set up promotional materials, prepared a theater and ushered guests as part of a Magnolia premiere screening.

# **PROJECTS**

## LOCALEYES

http://www.localeyestrips.com

An app that connects tourists to day trips curated by locals. Made in 7 days as a group project.

- Built with Rails 4 and the Materialize front end framework
- Incorporated Google Maps and Places APIs to retrieve information for created day trips
- · Used JQuery and AJAX for commenting, favoriting and communicating with Google Places API
- Responsible for styling and organizing inbox and messaging system between users; made use of the Mailboxer gem
- Assisted with the set up of Facebook OAuth and implementation of Devise security gem

#### **HOPSEARCH**

https://hopsearch.herokuapp.com/

A web app that allows users to search for numerous hop varietals and learn more about their attributes

- Built with Ruby on Rails 4 back end and React.js views on the front end. Utilize the Bootstrap 3 CSS framework for styling
- Incorporated the BreweryDB API for hop information as well as the Google Maps API to display a map of major hop
  growing regions
- Completed research to fill in missing gaps in BreweryDB API to create a unique information database for users
- Fully tested models, controllers and routes with RSpec

#### 256: A 2048 CLONE

https://github.com/jmcolella/2048-clone

A clone of the popular game 2048.

- Built using vanilla JavaScript along with the JQuery and Underscore.js libraries.
- Used object-oriented principles to compose game and determine logic for winning or losing the game.

# **EDUCATION**

#### COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY IN THE CITY OF NEW YORK

B.A. Film Studies 2013

Thesis: The tradition of "mono no aware" in the films of Yasujiro Ozu.

#### **DEV BOOTCAMP**

2016

19-week intensive program focusing on competencies in Ruby, Javascript and Ruby on Rails.